utb.edu 2009-12-18

# Privacy Statement

|  |   
---  
|   
---  
  
**Contact Us!**  
UTB/TSC Business Affairs  
Tandy Suite 100  
80 Fort Brown  
Brownsville, Texas 78520  
Phone: (956) 882-8240  
Fax: (956) 882-3868  

**Office Hours:**  
Monday - Friday  
8:00 a.m. - 5:00 p.m.   
  
  | 

**Web Privacy Statement**

The University of Texas at Brownsville is committed to ensuring the privacy and accuracy of your confidential information. We do not actively share personal information gathered from our Web servers. However, because The University of Texas at Brownsville is a public institution, some information collected from the UT Brownsville Web site, including the summary server log information, e-mails sent to the Web site, and information collected from Web-based forms, may be subject to the Texas Public Information Act. This means that while we do not actively share information, in some cases we may be compelled by law to release information gathered from our Web servers.

As part of our commitment to maintain the privacy of our Web users, The University of Texas of Brownsville has developed this privacy statement. The statement has two purposes:

  1. To educate users about privacy issues
  2. To inform users about specific privacy policies and guidelines employed at The University of Texas at Brownsville.

The University of Texas at Brownsville also complies with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which prohibits the release of education records without student permission. The University of Texas at Brownsville is equally committed to protecting the privacy of all visitors to our Web site.

* * *

The University of Texas at Brownsville Web consists of many Web servers. Some servers hosted by The University of Texas at Brownsville may adopt different privacy statements as their specific needs require. If another UT Brownsville Web server has a privacy statement that is different from this statement, that policy must be approved by the University compliance officer, and it must be posted on their site. However, those sites cannot adopt a privacy statement that in any way supersedes federal or state regulations.

The University of Texas at Brownsville web site contains links to many external Web sites. The University is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of the external Web sites we link to.

**Information We Gather**

Our Web servers generate temporary logs that contain the following information:

  * Internet address of computer being used
  * Web pages requested
  * Referring Web page
  * Browser used
  * Date and Time

The data is used in aggregate by system administrators and Web content managers to tune the Web site for its efficiency and is not ordinarily associated with specific individuals. 

**COOKIES**

Cookies are small pieces of data stored by the Web browser. Cookies are often used to remember information about preferences and pages you have visited.  You can refuse to accept cookies, can disable cookies, and remove cookies from your hard drive. In Netscape Navigator, choose Edit and Preferences to manage your cookie settings, in Internet Explorer select Tools and Internet Options.

Some Web servers within The University of Texas at Brownsville may use cookies to retain user preference information. It is against University policy to share this information with external third parties.

**Security and Accuracy of Confidential Information**

Although no computer system is 100% secure, the University of Texas at Brownsville has deployed extensive security measures to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of the information under our control. These security measures and our systems are audited by certified independent security specialists.

**E-commerce**

The University may enable you to pay for products or services online with a credit card. Unless otherwise noted, these transactions are encrypted. It is University policy that confidential information you enter in the transaction is used only for the purposes described in that transaction, unless an additional use is specifically stated on that site.

**Sharing of Information**

The University of Texas at Brownsville does, upon explicit request of users, share information with other parties and gather information from other private data providers. For example, the University receives test scores from testing agencies and will send transcripts to other schools. This is done only at the request of users (persons to whom the information applies). Unless specifically required under public information requests filed under the Texas Public Information Act, it is against University policy to release confidential information gathered through the Web, such as pages visited, or personalized preferences.

Consistent with FERPA, we do not release personal student information, other than public directory information, to other parties unless we receive explicit written authorization to do so. Enrolled students can restrict release of their directory information by contacting the Enrollment Office.

**Online Surveys**

The University of Texas at Brownsville conducts surveys for research purposes. At any time there may be online surveys being conducted on The University of Texas at Brownsville web site. It is University policy that confidential information gathered in these online surveys is used only for the research purposes indicated in the survey. Unless otherwise noted on the specified survey, your answers are confidential and individual responses will not be shared with other parties unless required by the Texas Public Information Act. Aggregate data from surveys may be shared with external third parties.

**Open Records Requests**

Except for educational records governed by FERPA, all information collected from the UT Brownsville Web site, including the summary server log information, e-mails sent to the Web site, and information collected from Web-based forms, may be subject to the Texas Public Information Act.

**Texas Public Information Act**

The Texas Public Information Act, with a few exceptions, gives you the right to be informed about the information that The University of Texas at Brownsville collects about you. It also gives you the right to request a copy of that information, and to have The University correct any of that information that is wrong. You may request to receive and review any of that information, or request corrections to it, by contacting the University's Public Information Officer.

**Questions**

If you have questions about this privacy statement or you believe that your personal information has been released without your consent call the Compliance Office, Rosemary Martinez, at (956) 882-8240 or via e-mail at [Rosemary.Martinez@utb.edu](mailto:Rosemary.Martinez@utb.edu).
